Guide to the Fagan Dickson Papers, 1950-1978 MS 281
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Fagan Dickson papers
1950-1978
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Dickson, Fagan, 1904-1977
MS 281
9.5 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
The papers of Dickson Fagan (1903-1977), Austin, Texas attorney active in the Democratic Party, include correspondence with both state and national political figures as well as Fagan's personal and business subject files clippings, published materials and notes, dating from 1950-1978.
Biographical Note
Austin, Texas attorney (1903-1977) active in the Democratic Party.
Scope and Contents
Papers include correspondence with both state and national political figures as well as Fagan's personal and business subject files of clippings, published materials, and notes, 1950-1978.
Correspondents include Dickson, James F.; Bentsen, Lloyd; Briscoe, Dolph; Buckley, William F. Jr.; Cranston, Alan; Carter, Jimmy; Domenici, Pete V.; Dugger, Ronnie; Fullbright J.W.; Ford, Gerald; Faulk, John Henry; Johnson, Lyndon B.; Jordan, Barbara; Kissinger, Henry; McCarthy, Eugene; McGovern, George; Maverick, Maury, Jr.; Moos, Malcom; Mondale, Walter F.; Moyers, Bill; Muskie, Edmund; Nixon, Richard M.; Pickle, J.J. (Jake); Richards, Ann; Thurmond, Strom; Weddington, Sarah; and others.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Gift of W. Hall via Ellis Rudy, 1978.
Formerly part of W. Hall papers - contact WRC staff for further information.
Index Terms
Subjects
Lawyers -- Texas; International economic relations; Politics and government
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); corrrespondence; speeches
Places
Israel
Subjects (Persons)
Fulbright, J. WIlliam (James William), Senator, 1905-1995; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973; Faulk, John Henry; Ford, Gerald, 1913-2006; Domenici, Pete; Dugger, Ronnie; Dickson, James F.; Cranston, Alan, 1914-2000; Buckley, William F., Jr., 1925-2008; Carter, Jimmy, 1924-; Bentsen, Lloyd; Briscoe, Dolph; Weddington, Sarah Ragle; Thurmond, Strom, 1902-2003; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhouse), 1913-1994; Muskie, Edmund S., 1914-1996; Richards, Ann, 1933-2006; Pickle, J.J.; Mondale, Walter F., 1928-; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; Moyers, Bill D.; Moos, Malcolm; Kissinger, Henry, 1923-; Jordan, Barbara, 1936-1996; McCarthy, Eugene, 1916-2005; Maverick, Maury, Jr.
Subjects (Corporations)
Democratic Party (U.S.).
- Series I: Correspondence, 243406
  Scope and Contents note
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Abourezk, James (Senator), 243521 (Box 1)
  - Alsop, Joseph, 243520 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, W.A. Jr., 243519 (Box 1)
  - Ball, George, 243518 (Box 1)
  - Ballew, W.V. Jr., 243517 (Box 1)
  - Barklay, John, 243516 (Box 1)
  - Baruch, Isak, 243515 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Michael, 243514 (Box 1)
  - Bentsen, Lloyd (Senator), 243513 (Box 1)
  - Berger, Elmer (Dr.), 243512 (Box 1)
  - Blankenship, John D., 243511 (Box 1)
  - Boorman, James A., 243510 (Box 1)
  - Boudin, Leonard, 243509 (Box 1)
  - Briscoe, Dolph, 243508 (Box 1)
  - Brown, George S. (General), 243507 (Box 1)
  - Buck, Pitman Jr., 243506 (Box 1)
  - Buckley, William F. Jr., 243505 (Box 1)
  - Bush, George, 243504 (Box 1)
  - Carter, Jimmy (President), 243503 (Box 1)
  - Chewning, Leroy, 243502 (Box 1)
  - Church, Frank (Senator), 243501 (Box 1)
  - Clark, Ramsey, 243500 (Box 1)
  - Coffin, Tristram, 243499 (Box 1)
  - Cooper, Bill, 243498 (Box 1)
  - Cranston, Alan (Senator), 243497 (Box 1)
  - Curley, James E., 243496 (Box 1)
  - Cushman, Robert E., 243495 (Box 1)
  - Domenici, Pete V. (Senator), 243494 (Box 1)
  - Douglas, William O., 243493 (Box 1)
  - Dugger, Ronnie, 243492 (Box 1)
  - Egan, Ed, 243491 (Box 1)
  - Ervin, Sam J. (Senator), 243490 (Box 1)
  - Faulk, John Henry, 243489 (Box 1)
  - Fisher, John B., 243488 (Box 1)
  - Fisher, O.C. (Representative), 243487 (Box 1)
  - Ford, Gerald R. (President), 243486 (Box 1)
  - Fullbright J.W. (Senator), 243485 (Box 1)
  - Gardner, J.W., 243484 (Box 1)
  - Garza, Kiha de la (Representative), 243483 (Box 1)
  - Glass, Frank, 243482 (Box 1)
  - Glubb, Sir John (General), 243481 (Box 1)
  - Hall, Walter G., 243480 (Box 1)
  - Hansen, Clifford P. (Senator), 243479 (Box 1)
  - Harthe, Vance (Senator), 243478 (Box 1)
  - Haynes, Marvin J., 243477 (Box 1)
  - Hilmy, H.E. Amin II, 243476 (Box 1)
  - Horsbrugh, Patrick, 243475 (Box 1)
  - Humphrey, Herbert H. (Senator), 243474 (Box 1)
  - Hutchins, Robert M., 243473 (Box 1)
  - Jabara, Abdeen, 243472 (Box 1)
  - Jacobs, Harry, 243471 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (President) - general correspondence, 243470 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (President) - clipping file, 243469 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (President) - 1960 election, 243468 (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. (President) - Civil Rights, 243467 (Box 2)
  - Jordan, Barbara (Representative), 243466 (Box 2)
  - Keeton, Page, 243465 (Box 2)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 243464 (Box 2)
  - Kritzeck, James, 243463 (Box 2)
  - Levinson, Morris, 243462 (Box 2)
  - Lilienthal, Alfred M., 243461 (Box 2)
  - McCarthy, Eugene (Senator), 243460 (Box 2)
  - McGovern, George (Senator), 243459 (Box 2)
  - McHugh, James D., 243458 (Box 2)
  - Mallison, W.T. Jr., 243457 (Box 2)
  - Marretos, Sam, 243456 (Box 2)
  - Marshall, Douglas B., 243455 (Box 2)
  - Maverick, Maury Jr., 243454 (Box 2)
  - Mondale, Walter F. (Senator), 243453 (Box 2)
  - Montoya, Joseph M. (Senator), 243452 (Box 2)
  - Moos, Malcolm, 243451 (Box 2)
  - Moyers, Bill, 243450 (Box 2)
  - Muskie, Edmund (Senator), 243449 (Box 2)
  - Nicholson, Hugh M., 243448 (Box 2)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (President) - correspondence, 243447 (Box 2)
  - Nixon, Richard M. (President) - clippings, 243446 (Box 2)
  - Nunn, Sam (Senator), 243445 (Box 2)
  - Olds, Greg, 243444 (Box 2)
  - O'Neal, John F. (Representative), 243443 (Box 2)
  - Overton, George W., 243442 (Box 2)
  - Owens, Charles W. Jr., 243441 (Box 2)
  - Parten, J.R., 243440 (Box 2)
  - Patman, Wright (Representative), 243439 (Box 2)
  - Pell, Claiborne (Senator), 243438 (Box 2)
  - Percy, Charles H. (Senator), 243437 (Box 2)
  - Pickle, J.J., 243436 (Box 2)
  - Price, Bob (Representative), 243435 (Box 2)
  - Rapaport, Albert, 243434 (Box 2)
  - Rapaport, Bernard, 243433 (Box 2)
  - Rarick, John R. (Representative), 243432 (Box 2)
  - Richards, Ann, 243431 (Box 3)
  - Rose, Donald C., 243430 (Box 3)
  - Sanford, Terry (Governor), 243429 (Box 3)
  - Schroeder, Patricia (Representative), 243428 (Box 3)
  - Sharlot, M. Michael, 243427 (Box 3)
  - Sharp, Eliot H., 243426 (Box 3)
  - Stein, Lou, 243425 (Box 3)
  - Stinespring, William F., 243424 (Box 3)
  - Taft, Robert Jr. (Senator), 243423 (Box 3)
  - Talmadge, Herman E. (Senator), 243422 (Box 3)
  - Tanas, George Botros, 243421 (Box 3)
  - Thurmond, Strom (Senator), 243420 (Box 3)
  - Tower, John (Senator), 243419 (Box 3)
  - Trimble, Seldon, 243418 (Box 3)
  - Tuchman, Barbara M., 243417 (Box 3)
  - Tugwell, Rexford G., 243416 (Box 3)
  - Tunney, John V. (Senator), 243415 (Box 3)
  - Weber, L., 243414 (Box 3)
  - Weddington, Sarah, 243413 (Box 3)
  - Willens, Harold, 243412 (Box 3)
  - Wilson, Charles (Representative), 243411 (Box 3)
  - Wright, Charles Allen, 243410 (Box 3)
  - Wright, Edwin, 243409 (Box 3)
  - Yarbrough, Don, 243408 (Box 3)
  - Young, Andrew, 243407 (Box 3)
- Series II: Professional subject files, 243292
  - Africa, 243405 (Box 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 243404 (Box 3)
  - American Jewish Alternative to Zionism (AJAZ), 243403 (Box 3)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 243402 (Box 3)
  - American Palestine Committee, 243401 (Box 3)
  - American Security Council, 243400 (Box 3)
  - American-Statesman newspaper ads, 243399 (Box 3)
  - American United - Glenn L. Archer, 243398 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 243397 (Box 3)
  - Association of Arab-American Graduates - John Faris, 243396 (Box 3)
  - Austin Chamber of Commerce, 243395 (Box 3)
  - Austin City Council race 1977, 243394 (Box 3)
  - B.E.F. (organizations and activities), 243393 (Box 3)
  - Business Executives Move (B.E.M.) - Henry Niles, 243392 (Box 3)
  - China, 243391 (Box 3)
  - Common Cause, 243390 (Box 3)
  - Constitutional amendments, Texas, 243389 (Box 3)
  - Dickson vs. Nixon - readings, briefs, orders, 243388 (Box 3)
  - Speech material, 243387 (Box 4)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 243386 (Box 4)
  - Foregin Policy of the USA (new; ), beginning 11-16-71; 243385 (Box 4)
  - FBI - Fagan Dickson, 243384 (Box 4)
  - Greater Austin Association, 243383 (Box 4)
  - "Hate" letters, 243382 (Box 4)
  - Aid to Israel - articles and letters, 243381 (Box 4)
  - ------- misc., 243380 (Box 4)
  - A.B.A. articles, 243379 (Box 4)
  - USDA Asc. Christian Co. office, 243378 (Box 4)
  - American Bar Association, 1958-70; 243377 (Box 4)
  - M.D. Anderson, Houston, 243376 (Box 4)
  - Askew Farm Services, 243375 (Box 4)
  - Austin Committee on Foreign Relations, Inc., 243374 (Box 4)
  - Austin Woods and Water Club, 243373 (Box 4)
  - Book of the Month Club, 243372 (Box 4)
  - Burns, Latham C., 243371 (Box 4)
  - The Center, 1969-70; 243370 (Box 4)
  - The Century, 1971; 243369 (Box 4)
  - Convocation Center at Houston, TX, 6/3/72 --; 243368 (Box 4)
  - The Center, 1972; 243367 (Box 4)
  - The Center, 1973; 243366 (Box 4)
  - The Center, Austin Washington, 6/14/73, 10/8-11/73; 243365 (Box 4)
  - The Center, Chicago, 11/3-4/74; 243364 (Box 4)
  - The Center, Santa Barbara, CA, 2/22/75; 243363 (Box 5)
  - The Center, Santa Barbara, CA, 5/10/75; 243362 (Box 5)
  - The Center, financial reports, 243361 (Box 5)
  - The Center, board meetings, 243360 (Box 5)
  - The Center, correspondence, 1974-75; 243359 (Box 5)
  - The Center, 243358 (Box 5)
  - Central Christian Church, 243357 (Box 5)
  - Christian Quarries, Inc., 243356 (Box 5)
  - Clayton Brokerage Co., 243355 (Box 5)
  - Committee to Impeach the President, 243354 (Box 5)
  - F.D. articles on Israel and Middle East, 243353 (Box 5)
  - Dickson vs. Ford, Judgement and Appeal, 243352 (Box 5)
  - Dickson vs. Ford, et.al., 5th Circuit Court, 243351 (Box 5)
  - Dickson vs. Nixon - misc. letters and articles, 243350 (Box 5)
  - Country Club, 243349 (Box 5)
  - Dixon, John M. Jr., 243348 (Box 5)
  - Dixon, John Sr. & Margaret, 243347 (Box 5)
  - Dickson - divorce hearings, 243346 (Box 5)
  - Dickson vs. Dickson appeal, 243345 (Box 6)
  - Dickson vs. Dickson, 243344 (Box 6)
  - Dickson vs. Dickson - hearing, 12/20/74; 243343 (Box 6)
  - Supersedeas bond hearing, Judge Herman Jones, 5/14/76; 243342 (Box 6)
  - Cataclysms & Miracles, 243341 (Box 6)
    (includes Dickson nameplate)
  - The Christian Century, 243340 (Box 6)
  - Democratic primary, 5/1/76; 243339 (Box 6)
  - Establishment clause (subjects of interest to FD), 243338 (Box 6)
  - Israel and the Middle East, 1976; 243337 (Box 6)
  - Israel, 243336 (Box 6)
  - Israel and the Middle East, 1975; 243335 (Box 6)
  - Israel as the 51st state, 243334 (Box 6)
  - Israel - misc. letters, 243333 (Box 6)
  - Israel - readings and evidence, 243332 (Box 6)
  - Mailing lists, members of Congress, etc., 243331 (Box 6)
  - Middle East International, Michael Adams, editor, 243330 (Box 6)
  - Middle East articles, 243329 (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 243328 (Box 6)
  - Office, 243327 (Box 6)
  - Religion, 243326 (Box 6)
  - Social Security, 243325 (Box 6)
  - Texas Bar Foundation, 243324 (Box 6)
  - Stocks information, 243323 (Box 6)
  - Travel - general office, beginning 9/69; 243322 (Box 6)
  - Zionist Organization of America, 243321 (Box 6)
  - Watergate, 243320 (Box 6)
  - Clippings on Civil Disorders Commission, 243319 (Box 6)
  - Est. clause correspondence, 243318 (Box 7)
  - Dickson properties settlement, 6/2/72; 243317 (Box 7)
  - Copies of misc. papers, PDD & FD, prior to 1973; 243316 (Box 7)
  - Mandamus and injunction in Court of Civil Appeals, 243315 (Box 7)
  - Temporary orders, 243314 (Box 7)
  - Killeen Legal Defense Fund, 243313 (Box 7)
  - KLRN TV, 243312 (Box 7)
  - The League of Arab States, 243311 (Box 7)
  - Militant Christian Americans - Lottye K. Keech, 243310 (Box 7)
  - Military Industrial Complex, 243309 (Box 7)
  - National Association of Arab Americans, 243308 (Box 7)
  - National Council of American-Soviet Friendship, 243307 (Box 7)
  - New Albany Bible Students - Mrs. David Doran, 243306 (Box 7)
  - Pollution, 243305 (Box 7)
  - Presidential campaigns, 1976; 243304 (Box 7)
  - Religion in Politics, 243303 (Box 7)
  - Religion in Outer Space, 243302 (Box 7)
  - Religion - 2nd coming, 243301 (Box 7)
  - SANE, 243300 (Box 7)
  - Texas Bill of Rights panel program, 243299 (Box 7)
  - Texas Bill of Rights foundation TV program, Middle East, 243298 (Box 7)
  - Tidelands newspaper clippings, 243297 (Box 7)
  - University of Texas Law School and Texas exes, 243296 (Box 7)
  - UNA USA, 1975-76; 243295 (Box 7)
  - World Peace through Law Center, 243294 (Box 7)
  - Yarborough, Ralph, 243293 (Box 7)
- Series III: Personal Subject Files, 243250
  - Admirals Club, 243291 (Box 8)
  - Austin Ballet Society, 243290 (Box 8)
  - Dickson, Fagan - personal correspondence, 243289 (Box 8)
  - Dickson, James F. - correspondence, 243288 (Box 8)
  - Dickson-Shapiro publicity, 243287 (Box 8)
  - Fishing, 243286 (Box 8)
  - Georgetown College, 243285 (Box 8)
  - Headliners Club, 243284 (Box 8)
  - Harvard Club, 243283 (Box 8)
  - Highland Lakes Golf Club, 243282 (Box 8)
  - Hunting, general, 243281 (Box 8)
  - Hunting, pigeon, 243280 (Box 8)
  - Hunting, quail, 243279 (Box 8)
  - Hunting resorts, 243278 (Box 8)
  - Hyder, Elton M. Jr., 243277 (Box 8)
  - Income tax, 1976; 243276 (Box 8)
  - Poster, 243275 (Box 8)
  - Kentucky Colonels, 243274 (Box 8)
  - Kentucky Derby, 243273 (Box 9)
  - Kiwanis Club, 243272 (Box 9)
  - Knights of the Symphony, 243271 (Box 9)
  - Law books, West Publishing Co., 243270 (Box 9)
  - Leases-Fagan Dickson, 243269 (Box 9)
  - Limousin Foundation, 243268 (Box 9)
  - Longhorn Club, 243267 (Box 9)
  - Medical-Medicare, 243266 (Box 9)
  - Names, addresses, files, 243265 (Box 9)
  - Philosophical Society of Texas, 243264 (Box 9)
  - Sargent, James, 243263 (Box 9)
  - Secretaries, 243262 (Box 9)
  - Senator's Club, 243261 (Box 9)
  - Smithsonian Institute, 243260 (Box 9)
  - Stites, Margaret, 243259 (Box 9)
  - Stock, 1976; 243258 (Box 9)
  - Subscriptions renewals and refusals, 243257 (Box 9)
  - Texas State Bar correspondence, 243256 (Box 9)
  - Texas Press Club, 243255 (Box 9)
  - Travel-safari and world trip, 243254 (Box 9)
  - Travel-South America, 243253 (Box 9)
  - Travis County Bar Association, 243252 (Box 9)
  - University of Texas, 243251 (Box 9)